uncommondesignsonline.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy and Cookies Policies - Uncommon Designs

Uncommon Designs found at http://www.uncommondesignsonline.com/ (“Website”) is governed by the following privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”).

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website.

WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW IS IT USED?

 **Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website** : We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form.

 **Comments:**  When visitors leave comments on the Website, we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

If you leave a comment on the Website, you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

If you have left comments on the Website, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

 **Media:**  Images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included may be uploaded to the Website. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

 **Embedded content from other websites:  **Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

 **Information We Collect from Others** : We may receive information about you from other sources.  For example, you may link your Facebook, Instagram, and/or Google accounts to your user profile.  If you choose to link your Facebook, Instagram, and/or Google accounts to your user profile, we will receive your name, email address and profile picture associated with that account.

 **Automatically-Collected Information** : We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

 **Cookies and Web Beacons** :

I do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit my site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit.

 **I also use third party advertisements on www.uncommondesignsonline.com to support my site.**  These advertisers use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on my site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit my site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to my users based on their visit to my site and/or other sites on the internet. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

Ad networks that may appear on my site are [Google Adsense](http://www.google.com/adsense) and [Mediavine](http://www.mediavine.com/).

 **More about cookies:**

  * Cookies are small text files that are placed on your machine to help the site provide a better user experience.
  * The cookies cannot identify you.
  * In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences and provide anonymised tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics.
  * As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better.
  * However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others.
  * The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser.
  * I suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at [the About Cookies website](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which offers guidance for all modern browsers.
  * To opt out of Google Analytics cookies, [visit this page at tools.google.com](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).
  * [This page describes how Google uses cookie data](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/) from this site.

HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

  * To operate and maintain the Website.
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters, blog post updates, and special offers. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings.
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts.
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries.
  * To provide you with user support.
  * To track and measure advertising on the Website.
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

THIRD-PARTY USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

Google Analytics – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.

Mad Mimi – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name (if submitted, it is not required) and email address for purposes of delivering such communications.  Please refer to the [Mad Mimi/GoDaddy privacy policy ](https://www.godaddy.com/Agreements/Privacy.aspx)for further information. If you would like your view and click information to NOT be tracked, please email me at uncommondesigns@yahoo.com with your request. If you would like to take care of this yourself, click the PREFERENCES button at the bottom of any of my emails.

This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

ANONYMOUS DATA

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

PUBLICLY VISIBLE INFORMATION

If you leave a comment on the Website, certain information may be publicly visible.  Your email address will never be available publicly.  At your option, you may also add an avatar, a profile description, and a link to your website.

You may also choose to link your Facebook, Instagram, and Google Account.

Users may see your username, avatar, profile description and website information.

 **Retargeting  Ads**

From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

 **Affiliate Program Participation**

The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

Uncommon Designs is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.  As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

 **Newsletters/Blog Post Updates/Special Offers**

On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify me at uncommondesigns@yahoo.com  to be removed from our mailing list.

Access – You may access the personal information I have about you by submitting a request to uncommondesigns@yahoo.com.

Amend – You may contact me at uncommondesigns@yahoo.com to amend or update your personal information.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that I erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to uncommondesigns@yahoo.com.

Please note that I may need to retain certain information for record-keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

CHILDREN’S INFORMATION

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at uncommondesigns@yahoo.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

CONTACT INFORMATION

At any time, please contact me at uncommondesigns@yahoo.com for questions related to this Privacy Policy.
